in this video I'm going to be teaching
you how you can edit viral Instagram
talking head videos completely from
scratch in After Effects I'm going to be
guiding you step by step in editing this
short you see on the screen right now to
do this we're going to learn how to
recreate all five of these animations
we're going to be learning how to edit
an engaging animation for the intro
three high-end animations for the body
and one final animation for the outro
and finally at the end of this video
we're going to be sound designing our
entire short using our sound design work
flow which we learned in this video over
here and here is a small snippet of what
you'll be able to edit by the end of
this video when I'm on a sales call and
the prospect just starts waffling you
have to actually learn how to use that
waffle to close them download the
project files and raw footage down below
so that you can follow along and without
further Ado let's get straight into
editing starting with our first
animation
here first I know I'm going to have one
big title animation for this entire
section here so I'll select all my text
and delete them then I'm going to extend
this text all the way and write out the
first part of my title which is how to
close then duplicate the text and write
out the second part which is wafflers
and resize the text until it is the same
size as the one above lastly I'll change
the second word to a more slanted font
and now let's create our text style
first I'm adding an ing gradient ramp
setting the start here and the end here
and changing my start color to white and
the end color to a gray to get this
gradient then let's add in a subtle drop
shadow and that's it for our main text
as for our special text let's add in a
gradient place the start here and
the end here then change the start to a
bright red and the end to a more orange
color let's once again add a drop shadow
but change the color of the drop shadow
to a dark red looks great now let's add
a little animation to the bottom text to
spice it up we'll move our play head
forwards and key frame the position then
I'm going to go back and move the text
down just a tiny bit and in My Graph
editor I'm going to click F9 to bring
this slide all the way here finally
we'll go to our second key frame and key
frame our transparency at 100 then go to
the beginning and make it zero and this
is what we're going to end up with this
is a clean and simple text popup that
just works but our text is looking a
little bit boring so let's pop it up
first we add in a light sweep effect
then we'll key frame the position move
it to the right side then move back and
have it start on the left side after our
animation we'll just move forward and
just bring it back to the center cuz it
looks really nice and in our graph
editor let's smoothen out the whole
animation and take a look at this
there's Improvement but we can do better
let's bring in a deep glow effect and
change the radius to 700 and the
exposure to 0.1 enable chromatic
aberration and let's paste the same glow
onto our other text that looks awesome
one final touch we can add is we'll add
an adjustment layer then bring the layer
down so that it's only above our aoll
then add a gajan blur and a brightness
and contrast effect and a deep glow set
the brightness to minus 100 and blur to
30 and glow exposure to 0.01 then bump
up the chromatic aberration select our
Circle mask draw this circle out and
lastly click on invert and feather out
the mask and we get this really clean
and simple overlay great start now let's
get to work on our graphic animations
first we add in a shape layer using our
rectangle mask let's draw out a
rectangle go down to the corner radius
and bump it up and change the stroke to
a width of two and change the fill to a
gray color and let's start by animating
our rectangle opening up to do this we
go down to our size function unlink it
and add a key frame for the current size
then we move back and change the x value
to zero and smoothing it out in our
graph editor this is what we get then
let's duplicate the same shape layer
select that rectangle and delete it but
now let's select our pen tool and draw
out a straight line then let's go back
into our scale and unlink it key frame
the current scale move our play head
back and change the scale to zero but
this will only work if we set our Anchor
Point to the center of our line and
reposition it with the shape layer okay
this looks really good but we need to
add in one final touch let's add in our
light sweep effect same as before let's
keepy frame the end of the animation
here and the beginning here now let's
add in a deep glow and change the
exposure to 0.01 and add a deep glow for
the line animation as well with an
exposure of 0.01 this looks awesome
let's go ahead and add in our icons I've
downloaded the camera chat mic and user
icon so I'll import those then selecting
all of them I'll scale them down and
place them here and just scatter them
out like so then select all of them add
in a tint effect and change the map
black to a white color then I'll make
sure the mic icon changes to a red color
to make it look special amazing now I'm
going to go ahead and select one of them
and key frame the current transparency
then move back and change it to zero
this will make our icon fade in and do
the same thing to all of them finally
I'll add an adjustment layer and add a
deep glow on top of it change the
exposure to 0.1 then precompose it with
the icon animations this is going to
apply our deep glow to the icons without
giving us any rough borders this just
looks amazing it's already enough for
the intro but there's one final touch I
want to add let's first rotoscope me out
of the frame by double clicking on my
layer clicking the Roto brush tool and
drawing me out of it then let's
duplicate the layer and delete the Roto
brush from the bottom layer now we can
start putting things in between me and
the background so let's start with a
shape layer by drawing out a rectangle
then rounding it changing the field to
Gray and adding our light sweep effect
now let's add in our user icon from
before and simply place it right here
add a gradient ramp and change the start
to White and the end to Green now let's
also duplicate the adjustment layer with
the glow and also precompose them again
and this all looks great but let's
animate them a little bit starting with
the shape layer let's key frame the
position go back and move it down and
the graph editor have it start quick and
then slow down then key frame the
transparency go back and drop it to zero
and mimic the same exact position and
transparency animation in the icon this
looks awesome now simply bring both of
these under our rotoscope so that they
appear behind me and wow that was a lot
of animating but we're almost done with
the intro let's quickly go ahead and
finish the rest of the text over here
it's going to be pretty easy so for this
first section I extend the words you
will have to actually learn then simply
go back and copy the effects from the
base text style here and paste them on
the first phrase go back and copy our
red text style and paste it on the
second phrase but let's quickly change
this gradient ramp to a blue gradient
and this looks good and as you can see
almost each batch of text has phrase one
with the white text style and phrase two
with the blue text style so all I did
here was apply the same techniques to
the rest of our texts so that we get
some really cool text effects on our
captions and with that being said the
intro is finally complete so let's stop
it off with some Zoomin and zoom outs
this will only take a second I add in an
adjustment layer and add in the
transform effect let's go to where my
icon popup happens and key frame the
scale in position then go back and start
it zoomed out then we'll move forward to
our text animations and just zoom back
out smoothing everything in the graph
editor and there you go you're
officially done with the intro man that
was a very exhausting intro but it's the
most complex part of the entire video so
we kind of expect it but let's go ahead
and give this a
watch all right looks awesome and if
you're about to lose hope don't because
this was just the most difficult part of
the whole video from here on out it
becomes super easy but if you're
watching this as a video editor and you
would love to edit videos like the one
you're watching right now I have a
program for you that can teach you
premere Pro After Effects and eight
different editing Styles in Just 2
months whether you are a complete
beginner or an intermediate in editing
these 300 plus courses will make you a
high quality editor with 50 plus courses
that will help you master Premier Pro 50
50 plus courses that will teach you all
of After Effects 100 plus courses on
short form editing Styles like Ali abda
Deon jao by maximiz and Houston cold and
100 plus courses on long form editing
Styles like imaji Isaac and my own
editing style we can turn you into a
Master Video Editor in just 60 days this
program offered through ultimate editors
is designed to help you become one of
the best editors by 2025 and start
earning money with video editing just
look at what all these guys have made
with ultimate editors in just a few
months if you're ready to Master premere
Pro after After Effects learn the eight
highquality editing Styles and even land
your first video editing client then
join ultimate editors the link is down
below I've left a completely free
6-minute video breaking down exactly how
we use ultimate editors to achieve these
results in the next 60 days but in the
case that this doesn't interest you
let's go back to editing now it's time
to create our second animation here now
this one's pretty easy so let's first
add in two shots of me working then
let's go a and delete all this text and
start by making a background We'll add
in a solid add a gradient effect
on it just change the type to a radial
ramp place the start here and change the
start to a grayish blue color and the
end to a darker blue and let's select
our Boll and using our rectangle tool
let's draw out a rectangle right here
this will crop it like so now do the
same thing to the second shot as well
and we're going to add in some cool
effects on the edges by adding in an
adjustment layer and adding a deep glow
to it and a gajan blur with a blur of 40
now select our rectangle mask again and
draw one out like so then just invert it
and add some feather let's tone down the
exposure of the glow to 0.1 and we get
this cool effect and that's it for
animation number two see that was easy
let's now get into animation number
three this one's going to be a bit more
complex first we won't need any of our
text so let's just get rid of all of it
now let's copy both texts from our intro
here and just paste them right here
change the first phrase to do not use
and the second phrase to phone and
resize it like so now let's create a 3D
phone animation first let's head over to
sketch Fab and download a 3D phone model
in gb4 import this bad boy into after
effects and make it the comp size and
make sure that that our scene is in
advanced 3D now you're going to notice
something our text just disappeared
that's because our Advanced 3D renderer
doesn't render out effects like blurs
and glows so let's precompose it and
change it to an advanced render all
right perfect let's animate this big b
first let's open up our orientation add
a key frame and tilt it like so then
let's move back and tilt it like so this
makes it so that it has to start like
this and rotate to a different
orientation then we smooth out our graph
editor like this looks good that's now
animated coming from the right side so
let's key frame the position move back
and have it start on the right side of
the screen then also smoothing out this
animation now outside our pre-m I'll
place the phone layer behind my red text
and simply change the placement of the
pre-m like this all right now let's make
this thing shatter first we add in an
adjustment layer and simply add on the
shatter effect change the view to
rendered and change the pattern to Glass
finally move our shatter over here where
the text was and let's change the
strength of force one to three and force
two to three as well and lastly let's
remove our gravity and that's all I want
to do with it so I'll just select my
adjustment layer and phone and both text
layers and precompose them one last
thing I decided to do is change the
viscosity to one which just makes it
super stiff and this is what it looks
like amazing so we've just completed
three of the five animations only two
more animations left before we do sound
design and complete it so let's go ahead
and work on our fourth animation now
this one is only a tiny bit harder than
our previous
ones but let's go ahead and dissect it
first we'll remove all our text then
copy the red text style from before and
paste it in and write out the word
Investments then we're going to change
the general color to to Blue then I'm
going to add a shape layer on top of it
and using my rectangle mask I'll draw
out this rectangle I'll go into my
rounded corners and increase it and
lastly add a gray fill and drop the
opacity then let's duplicate it and
place them both like so now let's head
over to Flat icon and grab an icon of a
camera tripod and an icon of a light
bulb I'll bring my tripod in and place
it inside my square like this then add
an ing gradient place the start
here and the end here and change the
start color to Blue and the end color to
white now let's add in an adjustment
layer add a deep glow to it and
precompose it with the icon we'll now
add in our light bulb apply the same
gradient layer on the same glow in
the adjustment layer I'll also add in a
light sweep to both our icons and now
let's get into our graphic animation
here I'll copy the background from
before and paste it here first let's
start with a shape layer and draw out a
circle and change the FI to White then
let's duplicate the shape layer delete
the circle and instead draw out a
rectangle here and Route off the corners
duplicate the shape layer again and draw
out a gray rectangle here duplicate the
shape layer again and draw out another
gray rectangle here and now let's meas
them all together using animations let's
select our Circle and key frame the
current scale move back and decrease the
scale to zero then smooth it out in the
graph Editor to get this popup then
select our rectangle unlink the scale
key frame its current size move back and
change it to zero and smooth it out as
well we select our gray rectangle and
key frame the scale at zero then move
forward and make it 71 and smooth it out
as well and lastly select our last
rectangle key frame the scale increasing
as well and smooth it out and there we
go now I want to create a camera and a
light so I'll duplicate the shape layer
once more and create a rectangle with a
triangle like this and this will make
for a camera icon then let's add a
gradient ramp to it set the start here
and the end here change the start color
to a light blue and the end color to a
dark blue and finally let's animate it
coming In by key framing the position
moving back and bringing it up to the
top of the screen and smoothing out the
animation in the graph editor amazing
now let's go aad and duplicate it but
change the shape to a circle this time
and place it down here then we're going
to keep in the position and move back
and bring it back to the left side and
smooth it out this looks good let's
finish it off with some line animations
by adding in a shape layer and using our
pen tool drawing out a line here adding
a stroke and adding some dashes then
let's make a draw out by adding in the
trim paths function dropping the end
value and the start value let's key
frame the start value move forward make
it 100 and we're going to get this line
animation so let's duplicate it and
place it here and duplicate it again and
place it here lastly to create a field
in between the lines I add a shape layer
and draw out this triangle and turn the
opacity down by a lot now I'll add a
linear wipe and key frame the start at
100% then move forward and drop it down
to zero and finish it off with some
Feathering too great so we have a bunch
of graphic animations and a bunch of
stuff happening on the screen now let's
make this look good let's add in a deep
glow to the circle here change the
exposure to 0.1 and the chromatic
aberration to 1% and let's paste it on
this shape this one this one the line
the camera the circle this line and this
line as well and with that being said
that completes our fourth animation so
let's go ahead and take a look at how
everything
looks with our fourth animation complete
there's only one last animation to be
finished finished and it's our fifth
one so for this last one it's pretty
straightforward I won't waste your time
on this but I first go through all the
text and reposition them and then add
the white and blue text styles to them
and at this point here is where we get
into our graphic animation at the end so
I'll cut my footage and duplicate it
then rotoscope the top layer so that my
top layer is just me with no background
then I'm going to select the base layer
and create a square mask on it and
finally I'll increase the mask expansion
at the beginning and key frame it then
move forward and decrease it back again
let's smooth out these key frames and
great this looks good now we add in a
shape layer draw out this rectangle and
add a gray fill to it add a white stroke
to the rectangle and finally let's add a
text layer and write out the phrase B up
front then let's duplicate it and move
the second duplicate to the top change
the text to be honest add some glow to
both shapes and finally we're going to
add in an adjustment layer with the
transform effect let's start the clip
zoomed in then let's move forward zoom
out a bit and zoom back in smoothing
everything out in the graph editor and
this is it it's finally complete all
five animations have been completed and
the shorts finally ready but there is
one final face we've created all these
amazing animations and it would be a
shame to just leave them there let's
bring all these animations to life using
our three-step sound design workflow
quick disclaimer I'm going to go really
quick through this section here but if
you want to learn all about this topic
I've made a 20-minute video covering
everything about it as you guys know
Step One is sound designing the woes
with movement so if we take a look at
our first section here it starts off
with a zoom out then a zoom into the top
right and a final zoom out let's add a
whoosh for the first zoom out here then
another whooosh for this zoom in here
then one final whoosh for this last zoom
out here and in this next animation we
only have one zoom in so we'll add in a
whoosh for it now in this section here
we start off with a zoom in and then we
have a zoom out then we have an out of
frame zoom out and a final zoom in back
here so for our first animation we're
going to add an a whoosh and for our
second zoom out we'll add in a subtle
whoosh and for the out oframe zoom out
we're going to have a very harsh whoosh
and one last harsh whoosh for the zoom
back in amazing now with our whooshes
out of the way we can move on to
textured sound effects let's start by
adding in a sound effect for the word
waffler popping up I'll use this sci-fi
sound effect here then let's add a
Sci-Fi sound effect for this rectangle
opening up then I'm going to add a
mechanical click for each icon and
duplicate it three times and as this
call pops up I'll add in a UI sound
effect and that's it for this section
when I'm on a sales call and the
prospect just starts waffling yeah now
this part here is pretty simple we just
have Cuts so I'll use a camera shutter
sound effect and overlay both Cuts with
it now moving on to this animation here
let's add in a sword swing for the light
sweep animation we have and we can see
the shatter effect here looks like glass
so let's add in a glass chatter sound
effect and that should do it the first
thing you need to be doing is not take
now this is a big one here but let's go
through it let's start with a cash
register sound effect for the word
investment and a UI click for each of
the two icons which pop up now for this
Motion Graphics here let's start with a
UI click sound effect for the circle and
one for the rectangle and one for the
other rectangle inside of it then we're
going to add in a gear sound effect for
this line here and duplicate it two more
times for these two lines that come out
here then a special sound effect for the
camera icon and a special sound effect
for the circle icon and that's going to
do it for this animation de just invest
in a camera and some basic lighting
place your camera right there place your
lighting right there let's just add in
two UI animations right here where these
two boxes pop in to make it look more
like a UI and that ladies and gentlemen
is how you sound design a very heavily
animated video let's add a soundtrack
and finish it off I decided to go with a
classical soundtrack for the video but
you guys can let me know how it fits in
the comments and there you go it's
finally complete all the animations all
the sound design all the music all the
captions everything and it's finally
time to enjoy it fully with the
animations it's sound design the music
and everything in between so let's go
ahead and give it a watch when I'm on a
sales call and the prospect just starts
waffling you have to actually learn how
to use that waffle to close them now
this is mainly speaking to those editors
who are looking to close more clients on
sales the first thing you need to be
doing is not taking these meetings on a
phone that's a big no no instead just
invest in a camera and some basic
lighting place your camera right there
place your lighting right there and
you'll be good to go and when you're on
the actual call just speak with
confidence be upfront and honest and
this is exactly how I handle it guys
thank you so much for watching all the
way till the end of the video it really
means the world to me I just wanted to
let you know that we are now posting
every single Sunday or Saturday for some
of you guys so stay tuned for our next
Banger that we've got coming up for you
God bless all of you guys stay tuned for
some amazing videos coming your way and
I'll see you guys in the next one bye
guys